<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel, Learn, Optimise on Mac &amp; Wen</title>
    <link>http://macandwen.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel, Learn, Optimise on Mac &amp; Wen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://macandwen.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 in Poland</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/post/covid-19-poland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/post/covid-19-poland/</guid>
      <description>Coronavirus. Much has been written on this subject in the past few months. However, many important questions still remain unanswered. How exactly does the SARS-CoV2 virus spread? Will a vaccine be invented? And if so, when? Can we avoid second waves once restrictions are lifted? How bad will the economic crisis be? Finally, could COVID-19 be a wake up call for humanity to start caring about the planet? Is it a warning that the earth is giving us?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wistow Crags Scramble</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/post/wistow-crags-scramble/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/post/wistow-crags-scramble/</guid>
      <description>A moderately difficult scramble in Lake District. Suitable for scrambling beginners/novices (ideally with some rock climbing experience) who are looking to verify and improve their protection techniques. No real exposure, many escape routes and easier alternatives. Good views at the top are a reward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Long Weekend in Lake District</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/post/a-long-weekend-in-lake-district/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/post/a-long-weekend-in-lake-district/</guid>
      <description>The spring of 2020 will go down in history as time of lockdowns, disease and social distance. However, in the UK, it&amp;rsquo;s not only number of deaths that has been unusually high for this time of the year. The amount of sunshine has already surpassed any other recorded since 1929; and that&amp;rsquo;s the state at the end of May, with good part of June (spring ends on the 20th) still left to make that number even bigger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be aware of the Future Travel Voucher Application from British Airways</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/post/ba-voucher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/post/ba-voucher/</guid>
      <description>DO NOT APPLY FOR THE BRITISH AIRWAYS VOUCHER, IT&amp;rsquo;S A TRAP Before you apply for a Future Travel Voucher from British Airways, you should know the following things that the official website hides from you:
 It&amp;rsquo;s a voucher not a eVoucher, so you need to call the contact center to redeem it (expect long waiting hours) They charge extra on top of the flight price for the services of booking with the voucher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New decade, new blog</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/post/new-decade-new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/post/new-decade-new-blog/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following our macandwentravelling blog, you would&amp;rsquo;ve noticed it&amp;rsquo;s been a little quiet in there since the end of 2018. With the onset of winter, weekend trips gave way to movie nights and museum visits, and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much to write about. Summer was short but intense, including a visit to Brazil and a road trip in Scotland (posts to come!). Then life got very busy, new job, new house, new routine - blogging took a backseat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A day in Bath</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/post/a-day-in-bath/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/post/a-day-in-bath/</guid>
      <description>As most of our readers surely know, United Kingdom in not the sunniest place on the planet. Amount and frequency of rainfall differs greatly between areas, ranging from an unimpressive 580mm of average annual precipitation in London (with a little over 100 rainy days per year on average) to 3500mm (and more than 220 wet days) in a small village in Lake District. To put that in context, Rome gets on average 800mm of rainfall per year, for New York it&amp;rsquo;s over 1100mm, Paris is 640mm, Berlin - 590mm, and finally, Barcelona - 640mm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Things To Do in Poznań</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/post/10-things-to-do-in-poznan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/post/10-things-to-do-in-poznan/</guid>
      <description>To start Poznań is not Potsdam. Potsdam is in Germany and has a beautiful castle; Poznań is a Polish city located west of Warsaw. It&amp;rsquo;s a student city with very cheap Ryanair flights coming here, so perfect for a weekend escape!
1. See the Billy Goats at midday The performance lasts around 5 minutes
Every day at noon, on the east side of the main square, two billy goats emerge from behind wooden-looking door and butt each other twelve times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Areas of the Region of Murcia</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/post/region-de-murcia-costa-calida/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/post/region-de-murcia-costa-calida/</guid>
      <description>The great thing about going to uni in the UK is the month-long Easter break, especially when there are no exams or deadlines on return. It allowed us to visit many different places and this year, Murcia was one of them. The main reason why we ended up there was a music festival called WAM Estrella de Levante, with Alt-J as one of the headliners. Realising that we might not get another chance to visit Murcia in foreseeable future, we decided to spend a day in this seventh largest Spanish city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parks of London: 10 Cool Things about Hampstead Heath</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/post/parks-of-london-10-cool-things-about-hampstead-heath/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/post/parks-of-london-10-cool-things-about-hampstead-heath/</guid>
      <description>Having recently visited and enjoyed Hampstead Heath (HH), we thought we&amp;rsquo;d share some photos and give you, Londoners, TEN REASONS to go there yourself.
1. Swimming We&amp;rsquo;ll start with the thing you might already be aware of - Hampstead Heath boasts three swimming ponds (female, male and mixed), which are open all year round and basically free (you’re supposed to pay, but no one bothers); they have lifeguards (well, does anyone care about that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpacking in Bannau Brycheiniog</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/post/backpacking-in-bannau-brycheiniog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/post/backpacking-in-bannau-brycheiniog/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;What the hell is Bannau Brycheiniog?&amp;rsquo; you&amp;rsquo;re probably wondering&amp;hellip; Well, if that&amp;rsquo;s the case, then we succeeded in drawing your attention to this post. Now, before we explain its meaning, let us&amp;hellip; just joking, no more stupid tricks. Bannau Brycheiniog is a Welsh name of a national park in the south of Wales, called Brecon Beacons in English. In this post, we try to convince you that it&amp;rsquo;s a nice place to go to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpacking from Hastings to Rye</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/post/backpacking-from-hastings-to-rye/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/post/backpacking-from-hastings-to-rye/</guid>
      <description>The first heat wave of 2018 stimulated us to go for our first backpacking weekend trip that year. Having very recently seen Rye ranked as one of the cutest small towns in the UK and recognising Hastings because of the 1066 battle, we thought a coastal hike from the latter to the former would make for a great weekend. And it did!
Hastings We spent most of Saturday in Hastings beaching, walking, chilling, gaming, eating and drinking beer beering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpacking on the Jurassic Coast</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/post/backpacking-on-the-jurassic-coast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/post/backpacking-on-the-jurassic-coast/</guid>
      <description>For the 2018 Spring Bank Holiday, we took off to the south of UK for some backpacking, wild camping and a bit of climbing. Our destination was the Jurassic Coast, which stretches for about 96 miles from Exmouth to Swanage and is known for its natural rock formations (such as Durdle Door), cliffs, coves and abundance of fossils. In fact, it is mainly due to that last aspect that Jurassic Coast was inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List in 2001, making it the first wholly natural World Heritage Site in the United Kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbing in Costa Blanca - Echo Valley and La Moleta</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/post/climbing-in-costa-blanca-echo-valley-and-la-moleta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/post/climbing-in-costa-blanca-echo-valley-and-la-moleta/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post in a series about climbing, which has become our big hobby in the recent times (inspired by Alex Honnold free soloing El Capitan - google it if you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard!). After months of practice in the climbing gym, the time has come to test our skills outdoors. Having already planned a holiday on the Spanish east coast, we were pleasantly surprised to find out that Costa Blanca is also a popular destination for climbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Fun Facts about Bruges</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/post/bruges/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/post/bruges/</guid>
      <description>Bruges (Brugge) is the capital and largest city of the province of West Flanders in the Flemish Region of Belgium (yes, their official language is Flemish [something similar to Dutch], not French! but let&amp;rsquo;s say they are not friends with neither of them historically). Its city centre is surrounded by canals protected by four town gates and it is sometimes referred to as &amp;ldquo;The Venice of the North&amp;rdquo; or even &amp;ldquo;EU&amp;rsquo;s Oxbridge&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpacking from Newquay to Holywell</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/post/two-days-trip-to-newquay/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/post/two-days-trip-to-newquay/</guid>
      <description>With the excuse of end-of-term and after successfully completing 10+ EXAMS (tough EE life), we headed to the west of UK in search of some waves.
Round train trip London Paddington to Newquay We found a nice train deal 2-weeks in advance - £22 pp round trip London Paddington to Newquay with GWR using the 16-25 young railcard (if you don&amp;rsquo;t have it yet, get it; trust me, it&amp;rsquo;s worthy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s see if this works</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/post/lets-see-if-this-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/post/lets-see-if-this-works/</guid>
      <description>Quick introduction - this blog is aimed to keep track of our little adventures, show off our pictures and in the meantime, give you some tips we wish we knew beforehand. We are two Imperial students based in Windsor - one graduated from Maths &amp;amp; Computer Science, currently doctoring at Oxford; the other, graduated from Electrical and Electronic Engineering and now working as a Systems Engineer at Cisco. We have travelled as far as Hawaii and as close as Chiltern Hills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leith Hill</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/post/leith-hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/post/leith-hill/</guid>
      <description>Leith Hill, at 294 m above sea level, is the highest point in Surrey and second highest in south-east England. Doesn’t sounds impressive? Well, it’s as high as the highest point in the whole of Lithuania! And higher than the highest ‘peaks’ in the Vatican (perhaps unsurprisingly), Monaco, Malta and Denmark! Jokes aside though, proximity to London and picturesque setting makes it for an excellent day trip from the capital.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://macandwen.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://macandwen.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve created this website using the Hugo framework. All pictures are original, taken by Maciek and edited by Wendy.
If you would like to use any of our content, please reach out to us at macnwen@gmail.com We are more than happy to do collaborations and would also appreciate any feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>